George Salter Papers, 1920-1980
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
- Series I. ARTWORK BY GEORGE SALTER, 1934-1967
  - Book designs (covers, book jackets, endpapers), [See Box 4: Folder 143a for lists of Salter book jackets arranged by author, by title, by publisher, and by date]
    - Viking Press Inc. (1935-1938, n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Viking Press Inc. (1952-1966, n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Viking Press Inc. (1954-1955, n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Whittlesey House (1946) (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - World Publishing Company (1959-1960) (Box 3, Folder 105)
      [see also Oversize Box:5, Folder:150]
    - Wyn, A.A (1945) (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Exhibitions, Graphic Works
    - Exhibitions: catalogs (1951-1962) (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Exhibitions, Typographic
    - Exhibitions (1945-1958) (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Typophiles (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Graphic design; announcements, advertisements
    - American Inst. Of Graphic Art (1941-1944, n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Basic Books (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Columbia University Press (1935) (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Colorgraphic (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Continental Typefounders (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Gebruder Klingspor (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Group Health Cooperative (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - John Peel Wiskey (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Klangfilm G.m.b.H (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Luria, A.N. (1938) (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - N.Y. Times Book Fair (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 120)
      [see also Oversize, Box:5, Folder:151]
    - Pergamon Press (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Invitations & announcements
    - Invitations & Announcements (1938-1966, n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Stationery designs
    - Letterheads (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Other graphic designs
    - Devices (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Unidentified designs (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 125)
- Series II. PERSONAL PAPERS, 1920-1966
  - Correspondence
    - Letters to G.S. from E. Dülberg (1920-1924, n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Letters from G.S. to different publishers: photocopies (1937-1966, n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Postcards to G.S. (incl. explanatory letter from J. Salter Rosenberg) (1924-1928, n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - To/from Chiswick Bookshop (1941) (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - From G.S. to E. Jungfer, notary (1963) (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Notes by G.S.: holograph
    - Notes (1962, n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Articles by G.S.: typescript
    - 7 articles, (6 in English, 1 in German) (1942-1964, n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Articles by G.S.: printed
    - Book Production Industry & other (1966, n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Cooper Union Art School
    - Mailing list :holograph (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Columbia Journal of World Business (Typographical Instructions 1965): typescript (Box 4, Folder 135)
- Series III. BIOGRAPHICAL PAPERS, 1940-1980
  - Articles about G.S.: typescripts
    - Article by M. Woods & G.K. Schauer (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Articles about G.S.: printed
    - 11 Articles in German & English (1940-1984, (n.d.)) (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Correspondence to A. Salter (1967-1980) (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Interview with A. Salter
    - Interview with Agnes O'Shea Salter (1979) (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - Obituary
    - Obituaries and letters of condolence (1967) (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Clippings, portraits, cards etc. (Box 4, Folder 141)
- Series IV. APPENDICES
  - Lists of books with jacket by G.S. (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Lists of German books with G.S.'s jackets (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - Lists of Salter book jackets in Series I, Boxes 1-3, (arranged/searchable by title, by author, by publisher, and by date) (Box 4, Folder 143a)
- Series V. OVERSIZE, 1936-1964
  - Book designs
    - Atheneum (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Fisher, S. Verlag (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Knopf, Alfred A, (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Longmans (1936) (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Random House (1951-1963) (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Simon and Schuster publishers (1935-1936) (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - World publishing company (1958-1964) (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Glass plate
    - N.Y. Times Book Fair (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Original artwork
    - Knopf, Alfred A., Apple in the Attic, by M. Jordan. (1942) (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Posters
    - Simon and Schuster publishers (1936) (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - Woman's Day, the A&P magazine, Men of Art (1946) (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Photographs: George Salter
    - Portrait, printed, black/white (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 155)
    - Portrait, printed, black/white (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - Portrait, printed, black/white (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - Portrait, printed, black/white (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - Portrait, printed, black/white (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - George Salter, teaching
    - 5 Photographs, teaching, b/w. (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - 7 Photographs, teaching, b/w. (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Agnes Salter (wife)
    - Portrait, printed, black/white (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Jane Salter (daughter)
    - Portrait, printed, black/white (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Negatives, of G.& A. Salter
    - Portraits, negatives (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 164)
- Additions to the Collection, 2004
  - Correspondence with James McCrea and Paul Standard (incl. explanatory material from James McCrea) (1957-1963, n.d) (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Original drawing for The Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Cloth-covered box designed for Radio Corporation of America (RCA). (Box 5, Folder 167)
- Additions to the Collection, 2010, Note: The 5 portfolios contain only the covers George Salter designed for American Mercury, Inc. In addition, there is a dummy for an edition of Shakespeare's works (never published?) that Salter designed.
  - Covers for Bestseller Mysteries (Porfolio A.1)
  - Covers for Ellery Queen's Mystery MagazineFall 1941-1957? (A.2)
  - Covers for Jonathan Press Mystery (A.3)
  - Covers for Mercury Mystery (A.4)
  - Miscellaneous covers: The American Mercury (1949); American Mercury Books; The American Mercury Reader; Bestseller Library; Bestseller Mystery Magazine; Bestsellers The Book of Wit & Humor Detective (1951); Detective Book Club The Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction (1950-1951); Mercury Books; The Mercury Library; Mercury Mystery Magazine; Mercury Press; Omnibook Magazine (1945); Page One Detective (1952); True Crime; Detective (1951-1953); Venture Science Fiction (1957) 1949-57 (A.5)
  - The Complete Works of William Shakespeare. New York: The Book Club, 1938. 1938, Dummy for a Shakespeare edition containing a few printed pages from the beginning of Hamlet, with a few drawings and notes by Salter. Never published? Lib. has 2 copies (not identical) of this dummy (A.6)